Nishanth Thiyakarajan

Email: Nishanth Thiyakarajan | Mobile: +91 9976738856 | LinkedIn: Nishanth Thiyakarajan | GitHub: Nishanth Thiyakarajan

PROFILE OBJECTIVE

Looking for job in data science domain with 1.5 years of IT experience where I can utilize my statistical and professional skills. As a passionate data analyst, I have completed some internships through some hands-on projects. Young and energetic individual with an agile learning mind who is keen to contribute to the cause.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tata Consultancy Services, Chennai.

05/2021 - Present

• Assistant System Engineer

- Automation of manual BAU activities through the implementation of SQL methodologies and Unix shell scripting with improved reliability and accuracy.
- o Creating and maintaining data in Clarity PPM as an Application ASG(Admin).
- o Raising, Maintaining and resolving the Change Requests(CR's), Service Requests(SR's), Incident Requests (IR's) for the applications in SNOW (Service NOW).

Data Analytics and Visualization Projects, GitHub.

06/2022 - Present

• Details of Data Science Jobs Python (Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn)

• Superstore Income Source Excel (Pivot tables, VBA)

Top 200 YouTube Channels
 Movies DB
 Tableau
 SQL(Basics)

• Website DB SQL(Intermediate) – used UTM's To get the Data.

Please Click Here to see the projects done in GitHub.

KEY SKILLS

• **Programming Languages** Python, C, Basics of Solidity.

Database Management System MySQL

Professional Applications Clarity PPM, ServiceNow.
 Software Tools MS Excel, Tableau, Power Bl.

INTENSHIPS / CERTIFICATIONS / AWARDS

- Completed the Certification of, **Python E2, MySQL E2** from TCS.
- Completed the **Tableau Desktop Professional** Certificate.
- Completed the Excel and SQL Internship at Pantech Solutions LTD.

EDUCATION

B.E COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

2017 - 2021

Kongu Engineering College, Perundurai, 75.30%

HSC 2016-2017

Rajalakshmi Gengusamy Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Pedappampatti, 80.08%

SSLC 2014-2015

Rajalakshmi Gengusamy Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Pedappampatti, 90.80%

PERSONAL DETAILS



Father's name
Thiyakarajan N R

D.O.B

29-05-1999

Languages Known

- English
- Tamil
- Telugu
- Malayalam

Personal Traits

- Resilient
- Leadership skills.
- Team Player.

Achievements

- Secretary for CSI (Computer Society of India) from 2020-2021.
- U-19 Kabaddi **Team Captain**.

Area of Interest

- Data Analytics' and Visualization
- Artificial Intelligence.
- Web3